Guide to the John Hay Whitney Foundation Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Administration, 1946-1994; Series I
  - Projects and Programs
    - Juvenile justice reform, 1977 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - La Raza Graphic Center, 1980 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Land banking of productive farm lands in Montana, 1977-1980 (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Litigation and advocacy on behalf of the rural poor of the Rio Grande Valley, 1982-1983 (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - Mass transit and community rehabilitation, 1978 (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - Massachusetts Urban Reinvestment Advisory Group, 1980-1982 (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - MATCH Fabric Company, 1982 (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - Mexican American Equal Rights, 1977-1978 (Box 31, Folder 15)
    - Mongolia County Development Plan (West Virginia), 1982-1983 (Box 31, Folder 16)
    - National Women's Conference, 1976-1977 (Box 31, Folder 17)
    - Nebraska Indian Economic Development Project, 1981-1982 (Box 31, Folder 18)
    - Neighborhood Institute (South Shore Housing Cooperative Network, Chicago, Illinois), 1982 (Box 31, Folder 19)
    - New Haven Food Cooperative, 1978-1981 (Box 31, Folder 20)
    - Niumalu-Nawiliwili Community Planning Project (self-help housing in Kauai, Hawaii), 1981 (Box 31, Folder 21)
    - Northwest Bronx Community and Clergy Coalition (Northwest Bronx reinvestment project), 1982 (Box 31, Folder 22)
    - Opportunity Fellowship Program
      - Correspondence, 1952-1969 (Box 32, Folder 1)
      - Photographs, Undated (Box 32, Folder 2)
      - Press releases, 1950-1970 (Box 32, Folder 3)
      - Publicity fliers, 1962, 1965 (Box 32, Folder 4)
      - Report, "The Opportunity Fellowship Program, 1949-1960", 1961 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Project for Action and Change in Education (PACE), 1982 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Plantation Initiatives, Louisiana, 1981-1983 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Portland West Neighborhoods (creating housing and self-sufficient venues in Portland, Maine), 1982 (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Preservation of the housing stock on the Lower East Side (New York, New York), 1978-1980, 1983 (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - Project to Monitor the Code of Discipline (Boston, Massachusetts), 1982-1983 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Public Pension Investment, 1981-1982 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Quilters Cooperative, 1978-1979 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Quitman County Development Organization (rural development center, Marks, Mississippi), 1981-1982 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Reforming government policies regarding community childcare (New York, New York), 1977-1980 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Reforming land ownership and use in the San Joaquin Valley, California, 1977-1981 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Renegades Housing Movement, Incorporated (Harlem, New York, New York), 1978-1981 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Revitalizing the Mission District (San Francisco, California), 1977-1980 (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Robert F. Kennedy Memorial Fund (board of inquiry on censorship of high school journalism), 1972 (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Rural development in Lee County, Arkansas, 1979-1981 (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - Rural homesteading methods and investigating the administration of comprehensive training act monies in Maine, 1977-1980 (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - Saguache County Community Council (local government action project, Center, Colorado), 1981-1982 (Box 33, Folder 12)
    - Skagit River salmon project (Upper Skagit Indian Tribe, Burlington, Washington), 1981-1982 (Box 33, Folder 13)
    - Small Hog Farm Advocacy, 1981-1983 (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - South Broadway Housing Cooperative (Albuquerque, New Mexico), 1981-1982 (Box 33, Folder 15)
    - South Bronx Housing and Economic development (People's Development Corporation), 1978-1979, 1981, 1984 (Box 33, Folder 16)
    - Southeast Women's Employment Coalition, 1980-1983 (Box 33, Folder 17)
    - Stabilizing housing stock on the Lower East Side (New York, New York), 1977-1978 (Box 33, Folder 18)
    - Sterilization abuse and informed consent rights, 1977-1978 (Box 33, Folder 19)
    - Tennessee Tombigbee research team, 1977-1980 (Box 33, Folder 20)
    - Thriftco Consumer Center (Jackson, Mississippi), 1979-1981 (Box 33, Folder 21)
    - Treme Community Improvement Association Incorporated (New Orleans, Louisiana), 1978-1979 (Box 33, Folder 22)
    - Unemployed workers in Rhode Island, 1977-1978 (Box 33, Folder 23)
    - Welfare Rights Advocacy in New York City, 1978-1979 (Box 33, Folder 24)
    - Whitney-Fulbright Professorships (Box 33, Folder system_indicator_ddf97580063b3abb9f6afe82a388601d)
      - "The Fulbright Professor Meets the American College", 1962 (Box 33, Folder 25)
      - Photographs, Undated (Box 33, Folder 26)
    - Women office worker project in Cleveland, Ohio, 1977-1978 (Box 33, Folder 27)
    - Working Women in the coal mining industry, 1978-1979 (Box 33, Folder 28)
    - Working Women Organizing project (Cleveland, Ohio), 1977-1978 (Box 33, Folder 29)
    - Zuni Craftsmen Cooperative Association (direct marketing jewelers-makers cooperative), 1981-1983 (Box 33, Folder 30)
- Fellowship Recipient Files, 1950-1971; Series II
  Series II is arranged alphabetically by program and chronologically or alphabetically by recipient's last name therein.
  The series consists of application files of John Hay Fellows, John Hay Summer Fellows, and Opportunity Fellows recipients. The files include applications with personal information about the recipients including name, address, education, and race; college transcripts; letters of recommendation; personal statements; and, in some cases, photographs. The John Hay Whitney Foundation records do not include files of unsuccessful applicants. Administrative records about these programs are located in Series I under Programs and Projects.
  - John Hay Fellows
    - Fellows (Year)
      - 1952-1953 (Box 35, Folder 1-21)
      - 1953-1954 (Box 36, Folder 1-20)
      - 1954-1955 (Box 37, Folder 1-19)
      - 1955-1956 (Box 38, Folder 1-20)
      - 1956-1957 (Box 38, Folder 21-30)
      - 1957-1958 (Box 39, Folder 1-20)
      - 1958-1959 (Box 39, Folder 21-40)
      - 1959-1960
        - A-K (Box 40, Folder 1-32)
        - L-W (Box 41, Folder 1-31)
      - 1960-1961
        - A-F (Box 42, Folder 1-33)
        - G-M (Box 43, Folder 1-28)
        - N-Z (Box 44, Folder 1-23)
      - 1961-1962
        - A-F (Box 45, Folder 1-25)
        - G-L (Box 46, Folder 1-18)
        - M-T (Box 47, Folder 1-24)
        - V-W (Box 48, Folder 1-10)
      - 1962-1963
        - A-G (Box 49, Folder 1-34)
        - H-P (Box 50, Folder 1-31)
        - R-Z (Box 51, Folder 1-24)
      - 1963-1964
        - A-D (Box 52, Folder 1-25)
        - E-M (Box 53, Folder 1-24)
        - N-S (Box 54, Folder 1-25)
        - T-Z (Box 55, Folder 1-17)
      - 1964-1965
        - A-C (Box 56, Folder 1-21)
        - D-G (Box 57, Folder 1-19)
        - H-N (Box 58, Folder 1-30)
        - O-Y (Box 59, Folder 1-24)
      - 1965-1966
        - A-L (Box 60, Folder 1-33)
        - M-T (Box 61, Folder 1-26)
        - W-Z (Box 62, Folder 1-9)
    - Summer Institute for the Humanities
      - 1959 (Box 63, Folder 1-50)
      - 1960
        - A-G (Box 64, Folder 1-48)
        - H-O (Box 65, Folder 1-30)
        - P-W (Box 66, Folder 1-41)
      - 1961
        - A-G (Box 67, Folder 1-48)
        - H-L (Box 68, Folder 1-39)
        - M-R (Box 69, Folder 1-45)
        - S-Z (Box 70, Folder 1-52)
      - 1962
        - A-D (Box 71, Folder 1-56)
        - E-H (Box 72, Folder 1-37)
        - J-L (Box 73, Folder 1-34)
        - M-Q (Box 74, Folder 1-46)
        - R-V (Box 75, Folder 1-54)
        - W-Z (Box 76, Folder 1-22)
      - 1963
        - A-C (Box 77, Folder 1-50)
        - D-G (Box 78, Folder 1-43)
        - H-L (Box 79, Folder 1-49)
        - M-P (Box 80, Folder 1-49)
        - R-Z (Box 81, Folder 1-63)
      - 1964
        - A-E (Box 82, Folder 1-74)
        - F-G (Box 83, Folder 1-26)
        - H-M (Box 84, Folder 1-68)
        - N-Z (Box 85, Folder 1-80)
      - 1965
        - A-F (Box 86, Folder 1-74)
        - G-H (Box 87, Folder 1-30)
        - I-P (Box 88, Folder 1-81)
        - R-Z (Box 89, Folder 1-85)
  - Opportunity Fellows, 1950-1971
    - A-Be (Box 90, Folder 1-66)
    - Bl-Ch (Box 91, Folder 1-83)
    - Cl-De (Box 92, Folder 1-67)
    - Di-Ga (Box 93, Folder 1-67)
    - Ge-He (Box 94, Folder 1-69)
    - Hi-Je (Box 95, Folder 1-66)
    - Jo-Mad (Box 96, Folder 1-94)
    - Mae-Ng (Box 97, Folder 1-81)
    - Ni-Re (Box 98, Folder 1-73)
    - Rh-Sh (Box 99, Folder 1-67)
    - Si-To (Box 100, Folder 1-81)
    - Tr-W (Box 101, Folder 1-66)